Guide to the WYBC, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Operations and Administrative Files, 1941-1971; Series III
  - Intra-station correspondence, memoranda, and reports
    - Programming department reports and schedules, 1949-1952 (Box 15, Folder 31 - 32)
    - Requests for Saturday supervisors, 1956-1957 (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - Voided check reports, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - Miscellaneous, 1947-1969 (Box 15, Folder 35 - 37)
  - Television station [WYBC-TV]
    - General [includes photographs], 1954-1955 (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 16, Folder 39 - 40)
    - Fred Waring College Program, undated (Box 16, Folder 41)
    - Organization of department, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 42)
    - Princeton Film News Center, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 43)
    - Scripts, 1953 (Box 16, Folder 44)
    - William Hogarth script, 1953 (Box 16, Folder 45)
  - Public relations
    - Copies of WYBC Microphone [newsletter], 1954-1956 (Box 16, Folder 46)
    - Copy of Yale News Daily and agreement with Daily, 1951 (Box 16, Folder 47)
    - Junior prom guests, Peggy Lee and Lu Ann Simms, 1954-1961 (Box 16, Folder 48)
      See also: Series III. Operations and Administrative Files, 1941-1971 Folder 70
    - Letters to freshmen, 1948-1968 (Box 16, Folder 49)
    - Membership lists and reunion activities, 1952-1969 (Box 16, Folder 50)
    - New Haven history, undated (Box 16, Folder 51)
    - Program guide, 1960-1962 (Box 16, Folder 52)
    - Promotional fliers and advertisements, 1960-1967 (Box 16, Folder 53 - 54)
    - Station history [clippings and written accounts], 1941-1971 (Box 17, Folder 55 - 61)
    - WOCD on the air: A history of the Yale radio station from its beginnings in the summer of '41 to February '45 and A concise statement of the financial transactions that are concerned with the founding of WOCD, undated (Box 17, Folder 62)
    - WYBC publications [ Microphone and program guide] and ordering information, 1956-1961 (Box 17, Folder 63)
    - Yale Alumni Magazine article about WYBC, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 64)
    - Miscellaneous, 1957-1963 (Box 17, Folder 65)
  - Photographs
    - Freshman show, [1962] (Box 17, Folder 66)
    - Interview with Virgina Baxter, 1952 World Olympic free skating champion, 1953 (Box 17, Folder 67)
    - Interview with Yolande Betbetze, 1952 Miss America (Box 17, Folder 68)
    - Ivy Network convention at WYBC, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 69)
    - Junior prom date, Lu Ann Simms, 1954 (Box 17, Folder 70)
    - Junior prom date, Miss Appleton, 1950 (Box 17, Folder 71)
    - Junior prom [unidentified female singer], 1953 (Box 17, Folder 72)
    - Scrapbook photographs
      See: Series III. Operations and Administrative Files, 1941-1971 Folder 163 - 164
    - Station activities, [1950-1955] (Box 18, Folder 73)
    - WYBC banquet with Ben Grauer, 1954 (Box 18, Folder 74)
    - Miscellaneous [Peggy Lee at prom, Smith College at Yale, station activities], [1949-1955] (Box 18, Folder 75)
  - Legal issues and regulations
    - Bylaws, 1961-1968, undated (Box 18, Folder 76 - 78)
    - Copies of arrangement between Yale Daily News and WOCD for break in relationship, 1943 (Box 18, Folder 79)
    - Corporation records and correspondence, constitution, bylaws, 1948-1965 (Box 18, Folder 80)
    - Federal Communications Commission
      - General, 1964-1968 (Box 18, Folder 81)
      - Challenge to FCC regarding drug lyrics, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 82)
      - Community surveys, 1974-1984 (Box 18, Folder 83 - 85)
      - Community surveys, 1977-1984 (Box 19, Folder 86)
      - Contested channel [FM 232], 1959 (Box 19, Folder 87)
      - Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 19, Folder 88)
      - License renewal, 1965-1975 (Box 19, Folder 89 - 92)
      - Licenses, 1948-1958
      - Notices on emergency broadcasts, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 93)
      - Schedule change request, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 94)
      - WYBC v. Federal Communications Commission [complaint against May Day 1970 live broadcasts], 1967-1971 (Box 19, Folder 95)
    - Programming contract [Timothy W. Powell], 1969 (Box 19, Folder 96)
    - Yale Broadcasting Company v. Allan Woods et. al., 1974 (Box 19, Folder 97)
  - Governance
    - Board of governors
      - General, 1962-1969 (Box 20, Folder 98 - 103)
      - Minutes, 1958-1963 (Box 20, Folder 104 - 105)
    - Executive committee
      - Executive elections, 1965-1969 (Box 20, Folder 106)
      - Minutes, 1947-1961 (Box 20, Folder 107 - 109)
      - Minutes, 1962-1977 (Box 21, Folder 110 - 114)
    - Faculty advisory council, 1948-1953 (Box 21, Folder 115)
    - General board, 1948-1966 (Box 21, Folder 116 - 119)
    - Student advisory board, 1967-1968 (Box 21, Folder 120)
  - Membership
    - Correspondence with Yale administration regarding membership lists, 1958-1962 (Box 21, Folder 121)
    - Deactivation correspondence, 1959-1961 (Box 21, Folder 122)
    - Problems with members' behavior
    - Lists, 1965-1970 (Box 21, Folder 123)
  - Fundraising
    - Alumni, 1948-1960 (Box 21, Folder 124)
    - Foundations [requests for grants], 1962-1963 (Box 21, Folder 125)
    - Fund drive and alumni reports, 1961-1964 (Box 22, Folder 126)
    - Fund drive responses, 1961-1963 (Box 22, Folder 127)
    - Phone drive tally sheets, undated (Box 22, Folder 128 - 129)
    - Solicitation for radio equipment, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 130)
  - Financial
    - General, 1959-1970 (Box 22, Folder 131)
    - Advertising contracts and payments, 1972-1979 (Box 22, Folder 132)
    - Bankruptcies, 1953-1961 (Box 22, Folder 133)
    - Ledgers, undated (Box 22, Folder 134)
  - WYBC events
    - Banquet for E. William Henry [FCC chairman], 1966 (Box 22, Folder 135)
    - Edward P. Clark Memorial Studio dedication and promotional package, undated (Box 22, Folder 136)
    - Executive cup and "How to be an Executive at Mory's Without Being Aloof" [song lyrics], [1963] (Box 23, Folder 137)
    - Twentieth anniversary banquet, 1962 (Box 23, Folder 138 - 139)
  - Professional organizations
    - College Broadcasting Affiliates, College Radio Network and others [membership information], 1962 (Box 23, Folder 140)
    - Intercollegiate Broadcasting System
      - Correspondence, incoming, 1961-1962 (Box 23, Folder 141)
      - Correspondence, outgoing, 1961-1962 (Box 23, Folder 142)
      - Newsletters, 1958-1962 (Box 23, Folder 143)
    - International Radio and Television Society and Connecticut Broadcasters Association conventions, 1966-1967 (Box 23, Folder 144)
    - National Association of Broadcasters, 1964-1966 (Box 23, Folder 145)
    - Radio and Television Executive Society convention, 1958-1961 (Box 23, Folder 146)
  - Ivy Network
    - Business advertising, 1951 (Box 23, Folder 147)
    - College reports, 1954-1955 (Box 23, Folder 148)
    - Correspondence, 1957-1961 (Box 23, Folder 149)
    - Declaration of Trust of the Ivy Election Foundation, 1968-1969 (Box 23, Folder 150)
    - Election coverage, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 151)
    - Expansion committee, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 152)
    - FM information, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 153)
    - Membership lists and spring meeting, 1968-1969 (Box 23, Folder 154)
    - Minutes, 1953-1959 (Box 23, Folder 155)
    - Minutes, 1953-1969 (Box 24, Folder 156 - 158)
    - News service, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 159)
    - Publicity materials [includes WYBC sample letterhead], undated (Box 24, Folder 160)
    - Rheingold Beer renewal report, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 161)
  - News clippings and scrapbooks
    - Clippings, 1941-1963 (Box 24, Folder 162)
    - Scrapbook photographs, undated (Box 24, Folder 163 - 164)
    - Scrapbooks, 1946-1962 (Box 24, Folder 165 - 167)
    - Scrapbooks, 1950-1961 (Box 25, Folder 168 - 170)
  - Summer broadcasting procedures and activities, 1968-1969 (Box 25, Folder 171 - 172)
  - Reports,correspondence, contracts [miscellaneous], 1960-1981 (Box 25, Folder 173 - 179)
- Advertising, 1954-1986; Series IV
  This series contains records arranged alphabetically that include contracts, broadcasting schedules, invoices, and receipts documenting WYBC's business arrangements with advertising clients. These clients included local New Haven businesses, non-profit and educational organizations, production companies, advertising companies acting on behalf of corporations, and celebrity agents. The series also includes lists of accounts receivable; records of station giveaways and public service announcements; and lists of the actual times that radio spots aired. The records in this series date mainly from the 1970s to early 1980s.
  - Actual times of commercial broadcasts, 1980-1981 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Advertising affidavit [Sorrentino's Appizza], 1954 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Advocate Newspapers, New Haven Advocate and television shows, 1981-1982 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Afro-American Cultural Center and Cabaret, 1978-1982 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Agora Ballroom, 1981-1982 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Allen Haymon Productions concerts and ticket giveaways, 1980-1982 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Aquarius Distributors and Arista Records, 1978-1980 (Box 26, Folder 7 - 8)
  - Aquarius Distributors, TK Records, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Arancio, Anthony and Peter, Paul and Mary concert, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Aries II, Inc. concerts, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Atlantic Advertising and Alta Advertising, 1976-1978 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Bill Beverly Advertising and Motown Records, 1977-1978 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Blue Jay Cleaners and Laundry, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Chapel Square Mall, 1979-1980 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Chapel Wine Shop, 1977-1979 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Client contracts, 1978-1981 (Box 26, Folder 17 - 18)
  - Colortyme Television Rental, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Columbia Broadcasting System Entertainment and Atlanta Child Murders, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Columbia Records, 1975-1978 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Connecticut Ballet, 1978-1979 (Box 27, Folder 22 - 23)
  - Cornicopia Productions and Yale Charities Drive, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Creative Source Productions and Oakdale Musical Theatre, 1973-1978 (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Cross Country Concerts, Earth, Wind and Fire and George Benson, 1978-1982 (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - Cutler's Records, 1977-1978 (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - David's Cookies, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Funkway Productions, 1978-1979 (Box 27, Folder 30)
  - Gypsy Bar/Guinness and Eight to the Bar concert, 1980-1983 (Box 27, Folder 31)
  - Hamden Photo Center, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 32)
  - Hamden Shoe Repair and Spectrum Christmas Special, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 33)
  - Heineken Beer, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 34)
  - Irwin Frankel Productions concerts and music festivals, 1972-1978 (Box 27, Folder 35)
  - Kaye's Art Shop, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 36)
  - Killowatt Productions, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 37)
  - Kinko's, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 38)
    - Free Enterprise Company, Williams Productions, and PHD Productions, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 29)
  - List of advertising sales and clients, 1961-1962 (Box 27, Folder 39)
  - Marstan Shoes, 1981 (Box 27, Folder 40)
  - Menar Productions and O'Jay's concert, 1977-1978 (Box 27, Folder 41)
  - Miller Brewing Company and High Life beer, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 42)
  - Minit Print, [1984-1985] (Box 27, Folder 43)
  - New Haven Food Co-op and Audio Replay, 1981 (Box 27, Folder 44)
  - New York Toy and Gift Shop, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 45)
  - Oakdale Musical Theatre and Jordan Associates, 1969-1973 (Box 27, Folder 46)
  - Pearson, Tony and Youth Club, 1977-1978 (Box 27, Folder 47)
  - Phil's Hair Styles, 1977-1978 (Box 27, Folder 48)
  - Public service announcement promotional broadcast orders, 1980-1981 (Box 27, Folder 49)
  - Public service announcements and press releases, 1988-1989 (Box 28, Folder 50)
  - Rhymes Records, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 51)
  - Roger Sherman Theatre, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 52)
  - Sales summaries, 1974-1986 (Box 28, Folder 53)
  - Scripts, [1975-1976]
  - Sherman's Tavern, 1981-1982 (Box 28, Folder 54)
  - Station giveaways, 1976-1981 (Box 28, Folder 55 - 58)
  - Subway, 1984-1985 (Box 28, Folder 59)
  - Sugarcoated Productions and Jean Carn concert, 1981 (Box 28, Folder 60)
  - Team Organization fashion show, 1981 (Box 28, Folder 61)
  - Tirrell Associates and The Driver, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 62)
  - Tommy and Kelley Enterprises, 1977-1978 (Box 28, Folder 63)
  - United Artists Records and Nineth Floor Advertising, 1979-1980 (Box 28, Folder 64)
  - United States Air Force, 1981 (Box 28, Folder 65)
  - West Indian Social Club, 1976-1978 (Box 28, Folder 66)
  - West of Eleven Restaurant, 1979-1980 (Box 28, Folder 67)
  - Whistler's, [1984-1985] (Box 29, Folder 68)
  - Yale Co-op, 1984 (Box 29, Folder 69)
  - Yale Repertory Theatre, 1980-1983 (Box 29, Folder 70)
  - Yale School of Music, 1975-1978 (Box 29, Folder 71)
  - York Square Cinema, Hearts and Minds and Tall Blond Man, 1974-1975 (Box 29, Folder 72)
  - Miscellaneous, 1969-1984 (Box 29, Folder 73 - 78)
- Audiorecordings, Circa 1962-1981; Series V
  This series contains reel-to-reel audiotapes broadcast by WYBC during the late 1970s and early 1980s. The audiotapes are arranged in alphabetical order within headings. The majority of the audiotapes are 30 or 60 second advertising spots for local New Haven businesses and non-profit organizations or national consumer products. A small number of the tapes contain programming material, including interviews, reports on community and social issues, and popular music.
  Original audio recordings may not be played. Readers may only play use copies. If a use copy of a particular recording does not exist, researchers must consult with the reference archivist for policies and procedures regarding the creation of duplicating master and use copies of original recordings.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  - Advertising spots
    - Alan Haymon Productions and Civic Center, Undated; 1 (Box 30)
    - Alan Haymon Productions, Hartford spot, and Toddy and Stephanie, Undated; 1 (Box 31)
    - Alan Haymon Productions and Chaka Khan concert, Undated; 1 (Box 32)
    - American Shakespeare Company and The Wiz, Undated; 1 (Box 33)
    - Archdiocese of Hartford and Christmas season spot, Undated; 1 (Box 34)
    - Archdiocese of Hartford and Thanksgiving spot, 1981; 1 (Box 35)
    - Archives for M. Thigpen [includes stereo store spots, movie spots, concert spots], Undated; 1 (Box 36)
    - Arnold's jingle tag and Bell jingle tag, Undated; 1 (Box 37)
    - Boston Globe, Raise the Titanic, Undated; 1 (Box 38)
    - Budweiser Beer and Hot Dog, Undated; 1 (Box 39)
    - Budweiser Light and Crowded Bar, Undated; 1 (Box 40)
    - Budweiser Light and Father and Son, Undated; 1 (Box 41)
    - Budweiser Light and Not Just Any Kind, Undated; 1 (Box 42)
    - Carrot and Casual clothing sale, Undated; 1 (Box 43)
    - Cinema Shares and Fists of Bruce Lee, Undated; 1 (Box 44)
    - College Street Cinema and Melody, Undated; 1 (Box 45)
    - College Street Cinema and Snake Fist vs. the Dragon, Undated; 1 (Box 46)
    - Concerts West and Stevie Wonder, Undated; 1 (Box 47)
    - Con Funk Shun, The Lady's Wild, and Too Tight/Touch, 1981; 1 (Box 48)
    - Connecticut State Lottery, Daily Numbers/Play 4, Undated; 1 (Box 49)
    - Crusaders and Crawford, 1979; 1 (Box 50)
    - David Ruffin, So Soon We Change, Undated; 1 (Box 51)
    - Deegan's restaurant, Undated; 1 (Box 52)
    - Dionne Warwick, 1981; 1 (Box 53)
    - Disabled American Veterans and Veterans Day, 1981; 1 (Box 54)
    - Fat Back and Let's Do It Again, 1980; 1 (Box 55)
    - Hall and Oates and I Can't Go for That/Black Spot, Undated; 1 (Box 56)
    - Hamilton Bohannon and Cut Loose, 1979; 1 (Box 57)
    - International Coffee and Orange Cappuccino, Undated; 1 (Box 58)
    - Jerry Gross presents Zombie, 1980; 1 (Box 60)
    - Kool and the Gang, Undated; 1 (Box 61)
    - Kung Fu and the Seven Drunkards, Undated; 1 (Box 62)
    - Labatt's U.S., Baseball, Burger and Fries, Mary, Mary, Football, Bartender, Jeans and T-shirt, and Study, Undated; 1 (Box 63)
    - La Toya Jackson and Night Time Lover, 1980; 1 (Box 64)
    - Millie Jackson, I Had To Say It, and Loving Arms, 1981; 1 (Box 65)
    - Music Systems Limited, Undated; 1 (Box 66)
    - National Dixieland Winners and Tommy Newsom introduction, Undated; 1 (Box 67)
    - Oakdale Musical Theatre, Bubbling Brown Sugar, Undated; 1 (Box 68)
    - Oh Happy Day, Undated; 1 (Box 69)
    - O'Keefe Ale, Nothing Stops the Wind, and A Man Can Take It, Undated; 1 (Box 70)
    - Olde English Beer, Undated; 1 (Box 71)
    - Pabst Brewing Company and Olde English 800 Malt Liquor, Undated; 1 (Box 72)
    - Reel to Reel Archive #5, Undated; 1 (Box 73)
    - Rick James, Teena Marie concert, 1981; 1 (Box 74)
    - Riunite Bright, 1981; 1 (Box 75)
    - Roy Ayers, Love Fantasy, 1980; 1 (Box 76)
    - Shalamar, Undated; 1 (Box 77)
    - Snyder Leather Warehouse sale, Undated; 1 (Box 78)
    - Southern Connecticut Gas Company and winter weather advisory], Undated; 1 (Box 79)
    - Springfield IV, Undated; 1 (Box 80)
    - Tech Hi Fi and pre-holiday sale, 1980; 1 (Box 81)
    - Tech Hi Fi and Christmas 1980, 1 (Box 82)
    - Tech Hi Fi and after Christmas 1980, 1 (Box 83)
    - Tech Hi Fi and August release, Undated; 1 (Box 84)
    - Tech Hi Fi and midnight madness sale, Undated; 1 (Box 85)
    - Tech Hi Fi, Undated; 1 (Box 86)
    - Western Union CCMO College Market [Vacation house, bookstore, car problems], 1981; 1 (Box 87)
    - Whispers/Shalamar, Undated; 1 (Box 88)
    - World Northal, Inc., Three Avengers, 1980; 1 (Box 89)
  - Programming
    - Career counseling for women interview [rough footage], Undated; 1 (Box 90)
    - Doc Watson, Sonny Terry, Brownie McGhee, and George Gretzbach identifications; John Hammond interview, Undated; 1 (Box 91)
    - "Yale Broadcasting Company Portrait in Sound," written and produced by Einar J. Westerlund, Yale '62, Circa 1962; 1 (Box 92)
    - Footnotes Master Reel #1 [short news segments on community and social issues; includes segments on local job program, federal criminal code reform and ERA/Women's equality celebration in New Haven], [1976]; 1 (Box 93)
    - Something Special, Dance and Sing, Master Groove, I Didn't Mean to Break Your Heart [songs], Undated; 1 (Box 94)
- Restricted
  Materials in box 95 are closed until January 1, 2047 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
  - Problems with members' behavior, 1971 (Box 95, Folder 2)